



WORK EXPERIENCE

Compass Foundry LLC (Owner)

(2019 - Present)

KINDBODY

(12 month Contract)

 Led design and full-cycle development of a new B2B product at a high-growth (\$1B+ valuation) healthcare startup. Reported directly to the CTO and worked cross-functionally with stakeholders to exceed original OKR expectations.

PFIZER

(18 month Contract)

- Served as product lead for the full-cycle development of a tool utilizing an AI/ML-based algorithm that assists cardiologists in the identification of patients who may suffer from a rare and under-diagnosed heart condition.
- Led the design and development of a mobile application for metastatic breast cancer patients from scoping the initial concept to discovery and development of the MVP.

BOSTON CONSULTING GROUP

(3 month Contract)

 Led a team within Abbott's neuro-modulation division through the scoping of a digital MVP product that pairs to a medical device aimed at reducing chronic back pain.

ANTHEM (6 month Contract)

- Served as product lead of a 12-member distributed team of designers and engineers building consumer transparency tools for millions of members. Set and managed performance OKRs.
- Led organization-wide design thinking and agile transformation initiatives as the company adopted the SAFe agile framework.

MyMeds

HEAD OF PRODUCT

(2015 - 2019)

- Led engineering, design, customer success, and clinical product teams from pre-revenue to millions in recurring revenue and multiple Fortune 500 employer and health plan clients.
 Managed up to 8 direct reports.
- Drove product vision, strategy, roadmap, and execution while translating high-level business requirements into actionable product features focused on engaging users while capturing high-margin ROI.
- Developed new business models and product offerings to capture revenue from diversified sources while maintaining fixed costs and promoting positive outcomes for patients using our products.

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

(2014 - 2015)

- Hired as the company's third employee with the responsibility of assembling a distributed team to build and validate a go-tomarket product and strategy.
- Designed and implemented agile development methodology while working cross-functionally with business, design, and engineering leaders to hit OKRs and manage scope/capacity.

North Labs

CO-FOUNDER & CHIEF PRODUCT OFFICER

(2015 - 2017)

 Co-founded a digital strategy agency focused on helping nontechnical founders launch digital products by intelligently combining US-based product and engineering leadership with offshore software development.

Epic

PRODUCT IMPLEMENTATION CONSULTANT

(2011 - 2014)

- Managed full-cycle implementation of numerous \$10M+ installs of Epic's Willow Inpatient Pharmacy application.
- Provided physicians, pharmacists, and executives with strategy and implementation recommendations regarding industry best practices.

GET IN TOUCH



www.nickguggen.com



nick@compassfoundry.com



ABOUT ME

Experienced product leader who thrives on combining data with empathy to turn business needs into engaging solutions that get results.

My experience building teams and products within digital health has offered many rewarding opportunities to innovate.

From leading product teams at Fortune 100 healthcare companies to launching and advising numerous health tech startups, I've dedicated my career to improving healthcare for as many people as possible.



EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin

B.S. Neuroscience & Philosophy Class of 2011 GPA: 3.7



PERSONAL PROJECTS

The Stoic Fellowship

CO-FOUNDER & PRESIDENT (2015 - Present)

Co-founded a multinational 501(c)(3)
nonprofit focused on helping to build,
foster, and connect communities of people
interested in studying and applying the
principles of an ancient Greek philosophy
called Stoicism. To date, we've built and
connected over 100 chapter organizations
spanning all seven continents.

Earn to Give

FOUNDER (2017 - Present)

• Founded a 501(c)(3) nonprofit that catalyzes corporate charitable giving by making it fun, easy, and social.

Fight for Fair

FOUNDER (2022 - Present)

 Founded a nonprofit aimed at helping patients navigate medication costs and insurance billing to get the care they need at a price that's fair.



HOBBIES







